<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>arch on Mads Kjeldgaard</title>
    <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/tags/arch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in arch on Mads Kjeldgaard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:17:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://madskjeldgaard.dk/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A portable Arch Linux Computer Music system on a USB drive</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/portable-arch-computermusic-distro-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:17:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/portable-arch-computermusic-distro-usb/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this blog post, I have been toying with a silly idea lately: A completely portable Arch Linux distribution set up properly for computer music, but flashed onto a USB thumb drive so that I may pop it into any computer, boot from the thumb drive and start creating music on whatever hardware is in front of me.
I have achieved this now using the awesome alma project. Alma is a tool for creating persistent USB installations of Arch Linux using a series of configuration files and bash scripts called presets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Windows VST Plugins on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/vst-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 12:20:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/vst-manager/</guid>
      <description>One of the big hurdles for me when switching from a Mac based audio setup was the potential loss of access to my expensive collection of VST plugins (because a lot of developers still ignore the Linux platform as if it was 1995 even though it has never been easier to make and release cross platform plugins). Little did I know that almost all of them would run just fine on Linux using the wine Windows compatibility layer and the linvst VST plugin bridging software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on creating packages for the Arch User Repository (AUR)</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/aur-package-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 22:51:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/aur-package-workflow/</guid>
      <description>These are notes I have been taking while making packages for the Arch User Repository, a community based package repository for users of Arch Linux and it&amp;rsquo;s derivative operating systems. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete guide and certainly not beginner friendly but should help some people with some linux experience get started.
If you have a tolerance for YouTube videos, then maybe this video will be helpful to you.
It is also recommend to read the official guide on how to create packages: Creating packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
