<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cpp on Mads Kjeldgaard</title>
    <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/tags/cpp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cpp on Mads Kjeldgaard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:16:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://madskjeldgaard.dk/tags/cpp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A midi controller in a box of screws</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/master-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/master-volume/</guid>
      <description>I recently built version 2 of a &amp;ldquo;master volume control&amp;rdquo; midi controller that I had made before. This version is slightly improved on the former.
It is very cheap and simple. It revolves around the wonderful and cheap (11$) Teensy LC.
Bill of materials includes:
 A 10k potentiometer A button A Teensy LC A box (I used a leftover box that had contained some wood screws - perfect size!) A few wires (Optionally) A 3D-printed bracket to mount the Teensy to the side of the box  All code and notes for building may be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutable Instruments dev environment on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/mutable-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 13:39:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/mutable-dev/</guid>
      <description>Mutable Instruments is an absolutely amazing synthesizer company that produces open source hardware with open source firmware on it. I have several of these and I love poking around in the firmware (check out this brilliant tutorial om how to do the same).
The company has even open sourced it&amp;rsquo;s development environment which on most systems may be setup in a virtual machine.
But this is not so easy on Arch Linux, since these virtual machines rely on old(er) kernels, and I am always on bleeding edge kernel versions on my development laptop, so I decided to setup my own little development environment for hacking Mutable Instruments (and similar) firmwares directly in Arch with no virtual machines used and it seems to work quite nicely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpful SuperCollider plugin macros</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/helpful-sc-plugin-macros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 21:38:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/helpful-sc-plugin-macros/</guid>
      <description>This is a transcription of Dan Stowell&amp;rsquo;s very helpful table in the SuperCollider Book (MIT), slightly edited and transcribed for the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; c++ style for writing plugins. It contains some of the macros available when writing UGens/Plugins in c++ in SuperCollider.
This repo contains example code for writing plugins in both the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; style which I found helpful in understanding this subject.
Also check out this cookiecutter template for generating plugins and the Server Plugin API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on writing SuperCollider plugins</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/notes-on-writing-sc-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 21:38:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/notes-on-writing-sc-plugins/</guid>
      <description>This post is a collection of notes on how to write plugins for SuperCollider.
This post will be updated as I go along.
Useful links This repo contains example code for writing plugins in both the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; style which I found helpful in understanding this subject.
Also check out this cookiecutter template for generating plugins and the Server Plugin API.
The two different styles There are two different headers that contain SuperCollider&amp;rsquo;s plugin boiler plate code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeoVim setup for c&#43;&#43; and openFrameworks development</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/neovim-setup-for-c-and-openframeworks-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 15:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/neovim-setup-for-c-and-openframeworks-development/</guid>
      <description>It is possible to get a nice development environment on Linux (and other platforms) using NeoVim and a few plugins and settings.
This dev environment includes snippets, autocomplete, debugging and smart code suggestions for methods.
I got a lot of pointers for this setup from Chendi Xue’s blogpost about Vim/CPP development.
So, without further ado here are my notes for setting up shop using YouCompleteMe, UltiSnips and some formatting plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
