<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wine on Mads Kjeldgaard</title>
    <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/tags/wine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wine on Mads Kjeldgaard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:13:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://madskjeldgaard.dk/tags/wine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improve Windows VST plugin performance on Arch using Wine TKG</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/improve-vst-performance-wine-tkg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:13:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/improve-vst-performance-wine-tkg/</guid>
      <description>I do all of my production work on Arch-based Linux systems these days. This is generally a pleasent experience since Reaper started supporting native Linux builds and yabridgectl made bridging Windows VST Plugins quite breezy and effective. Once setup correctly, this offers a performance experience and workflow that I think is quite close to native.
One advice that I kept hearing again and again though was to install wine (the Wine program that lets you use Windows software on Linux) using wine-tkg, a customized build system for installing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Windows VST Plugins on Arch Linux and Manjaro</title>
      <link>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/vst-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 12:20:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madskjeldgaard.dk/posts/vst-manager/</guid>
      <description>One of the big hurdles for me when switching from a Mac based audio setup was the potential loss of access to my expensive collection of VST plugins (because a lot of developers still ignore the Linux platform as if it was 1995 even though it has never been easier to make and release cross platform plugins). Little did I know that almost all of them would run just fine on Linux using the wine Windows compatibility layer and the yabridge or linvst VST plugin bridging software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
